Meet Your Maker.
Dead Space: Downfall is a animation, horror, science
fiction film directed by Chuck Patton.
On a deep space mining mission to a remote planet, an ancient religious relic - thought
to be proof of the existence of God - is unearthed and brought aboard.
When the unholy artifact unleashes a long-dormant alien race, its
glimpse of Heaven transforms the ship into a living Hell.
A prequel to the events of the 2008 video game Dead Space.
Colin Barrow (voice), played by Bruce Boxleitner.
Heather / Donna Fawkes (voice), played by Grey DeLisle.
Leggio / Dobbs / Jackson (voice), played by Jeff Bennett.
Captain Mathius / Farum (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
Jen Barrow (voice), played by Lia Sargent.
Alissa Vincent (voice), played by Nika Futterman.
Dead Space: Downfall is a 2008 American adult animated psychological science fiction horror film directed by Chuck Patton, written by Justin Gray and Jimmy Palmiotti and developed
by Film Roman under the supervision of Electronic Arts; Electronic Arts also published the 2008 survival horror video game Dead Space upon which the film is based.
It first released direct-to-video in October, before seeing a
television showing the following month on Starz Encore.
Downfall is a prequel to Dead Space, taking place
after the limited comic series.
Set aboard the planet mining ship USG Ishimura, it details the events following the transportation of an artifact called the Marker from the
planet Aegis VII, leading to the deaths of nearly everyone on board at the hands of reanimated mutated corpses dubbed "Necromorphs".
The film was produced as part of Electronic Art's multimedia
expansion of the plot, referred to by staff as "IP cubed".
Patton was given relative freedom with the narrative and visuals, wanting
to create the goriest feature Film Roman had produced.
Electronic Arts provided art assets to Film Roman, allowing an
accurate representation of the game's universe.
The DVD release earned over $1 million in sales.
Reviews were mixed, with praise for its voice acting, writing and animation, but criticism for
its short length and emphasis on graphic violence over horror and suspense.
Electronic Arts and Film Roman would collaborate again on 2011's
Dead Space: Aftermath, a prequel to Dead Space 2.
The film explores themes of colony, vacuum, fanatic, infection, adult animation.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.